everybody wanted the atat from the Star Wars wow it's a really exciting toy or is it yeah his legs moving that and
每个人都想要《星球大战》中的 atat 哇，这是一个非常令人兴奋的玩具，或者是他的腿在移动，
the 80s ones had guns that moved and lit up but you have to put your hand in to operate its head and
80年代的枪可以移动并发光，但你必须把手伸进去才能操作它的头部
yeah the legs move if you operate them with your hands wouldn't it be better if it walked along now I'm aware of
是的，如果你用手操作腿就会移动，如果它现在走路不是更好吗我知道
a walking at a tea toy
一个在茶馆散步的玩具
which was made by thinkway but this was quite a bit smaller and
这是由 thinkway 制作的，但是要小一些
didn't really walk amazingly well mostly its feet are just sliding on the ground I suspect it had a similar mechanism to the
行走得并不好，大部分时候它的脚只是在地面上滑动，我怀疑它有一个与
3D printed ones
3D打印的
that have been going around and ultimately that's because licensed toys cost a lot to produce so cutting down on Motors and
这种情况一直存在，最终是因为授权玩具的生产成本很高，因此减少了汽车和
control Electronics is generally how things go in the toy industry otherwise the product ends up costing too much I've built quite a
控制电子产品通常是玩具行业的发展方式，否则产品最终会花费太多我已经建造了相当多的
few four-legged walking robots in the past I spent years through multiple versions of robot dogs before I got to something
过去很少有四足步行机器人 我花了数年时间研究多个版本的机器狗，然后才得到一些东西
that could move fast and was Dynamic but I actually started with bipedal robots like my the Star Wars gonk droid which
它可以快速移动并且是动态的，但实际上我是从双足机器人开始的，比如我的星球大战贡克机器人
walked Along on two legs at the time I thought if I can make something not too bad that walks on two legs
两条腿走路 当时就想能不能做出一个两条腿走路的东西还不错
and four legs should be easy but what I didn't consider was that the gong drop had big flat feet and
四条腿应该很容易，但我没有考虑到锣坠有大平脚，
typically robot dogs have much smaller pointy feet which is why it took me so very many versions to make a robot dog
通常机器狗的脚要小得多，这就是为什么我花了很多版本来制作机器狗
that walked well but I never went back to build a four-legged walking robot with big flat feet to see how easy that
行走得很好，但我从来没有回去建造一个带有大平脚的四足行走机器人，看看这有多容易
would be and the at 80 is a great robot to convert because
would be and the at 80 is a great robot to convert because
it's got these great big flat feet with these stabilizing toes I'm going to use a very similar parallelogram leg mechanism to the
它有这些巨大的扁平足和这些稳定的脚趾，我将使用与
gong Droid
锣机器人
which had a gear reduction built into the leg I worked out the geometry for this in the gong Droid series which
它的腿上内置了一个齿轮减速器，我在锣 Droid 系列中计算出了它的几何形状，
you can check out in my channel essentially though it's a motor with a Spur Gear Running on a large partial gear and
你可以在我的频道中查看本质上，尽管它是一个带有正齿轮的电机，在一个大的部分齿轮上运行并且
as I demonstrated in the previous videos the large gear just needs to be the same radius as the top part of the
正如我在之前的视频中演示的那样，大齿轮只需与齿轮顶部的半径相同即可
parallelogram and
平行四边形和
then the gears track each other just fine instead of a DC motor this time I'm going to use some servos with a
然后齿轮可以很好地相互跟踪，而不是直流电机，这次我将使用一些伺服系统
gear mounted on the servo horn just a quick ad for my 3D printing sponsor thanks to lol's bar for supporting my Channel
安装在伺服喇叭上的齿轮只是我的 3D 打印赞助商的一个快速广告，感谢 lol 酒吧对我频道的支持
with 3D printers having lots of printers really helps get the projects done in time obviously we have to make four of everything
使用 3D 打印机 拥有大量打印机确实有助于及时完成项目，显然我们必须制作四件东西
because it has four legs and in some cases that's actually more parts the legs themselves have four sections so
because it has four legs and in some cases that's actually more parts the legs themselves have four sections so
we have to make 16 sticks to make our four parallelogram legs and here's one of the gears that
we have to make 16 sticks to make our four parallelogram legs and here's one of the gears that
goes on the servo right all my parts are printed so
位于伺服右侧，我的所有零件都已打印，所以
we're ready to do some assembly thanks to 3D fuel for the filament for this this is all pro pla plus so
由于灯丝的 3D 燃料，我们已经准备好进行一些组装，因为这都是 pro pla plus 所以
here are my gears for the servo there's a recess so that that
here are my gears for the servo there's a recess so that that
gear can get really close to the servo body but obviously those little things sticking up are probably going to snap off it'll
gear can get really close to the servo body but obviously those little things sticking up are probably going to snap off it'll
be okay though
不过没关系
because the bulk of the gear is just fine the servo itself fits into a Servo bracket which is 3D printed and
because the bulk of the gear is just fine the servo itself fits into a Servo bracket which is 3D printed and
yes I remember to leave the hole for the cable to come out just on the end there so
是的，我记得在末端留下一个孔，以便电缆出来，这样
we can screw them in
我们可以把它们拧进去
that bracket fits onto one of the pieces of the leg there and obviously there's a recess so that
该支架安装在腿的其中一个部件上，显然有一个凹槽，以便
the gear can turn without binding on it
齿轮可以转动而不受其束缚
the other side of the leg has that partial spur gear on and that binds nicely onto the gear that we've got so
腿的另一侧有部分正齿轮，它很好地结合到我们拥有的齿轮上
now we just need to install something on each end so that we've got our parallelogram I've got some three millimeter steel axles
现在我们只需要在两端安装一些东西，这样我们就得到了平行四边形我有一些三毫米钢轴
so now we can put together the parallelogram and now we've got a working mechanism with a motor in it so giving that
所以现在我们可以把平行四边形放在一起，现在我们有了一个带有电机的工作机构，所以给出
Servo a signal on some power we can see that moves quite nicely and that Servo tracks the big gear perfectly just because
伺服系统发出一些功率信号，我们可以看到它移动得非常好，并且伺服系统完美地跟踪大齿轮，因为
the big gear is the same radius as the top part of the parallelogram so
大齿轮的半径与平行四边形顶部的半径相同，因此
that's worked out well again really happy if how that's turned out there's hardly any slop in this as well so
一切又顺利了，如果结果如何，这也几乎没有任何问题的话，我真的很高兴，所以
it's actually quite a rigid mechanism so with these stages stacked together there's going to be hardly any wobble in the legs so
它实际上是一个相当刚性的机构，因此将这些阶段堆叠在一起后，腿部几乎不会晃动，因此
all we need to do now is build the top of the leg and then build four more of them and
我们现在需要做的就是建造腿的顶部，然后再建造四个
put it all together so here's one whole leg with its two stages so it can bend in the middle so that
把它们放在一起，这是一条完整的腿，有两个阶段，这样它就可以在中间弯曲，这样
gives us quite a wide range of motion we've got a big enough stripe there to walk like an AT-AT and
为我们提供了相当大的运动范围，我们有足够大的条纹，可以像 AT-AT 一样行走
of course we can bend the leg as well to pick it up so
当然我们也可以弯曲腿来捡起它
if we Bend both Motors in the same direction then we can pick the leg up and that
如果我们向同一方向弯曲两个电机，那么我们可以抬起腿，然后
gives us enough ground clearance to take steps but before we put the rest of the parts for that
为我们提供了足够的离地间隙来采取措施，但在我们放置其余零件之前
together it's time for a quick ad from the video sponsor which is curiositystream curiosity stream offers many award-winning documentary series that
现在是视频赞助商的快速广告的时候了，好奇心流提供了许多获奖的纪录片系列，
you can't find anywhere else the content spans many factual topics including science technology engineering nature history food and lots lots more so
您在其他任何地方都找不到该内容涵盖许多事实主题，包括科学技术、工程、自然历史、食品等等。
there's something for everyone curiosity stream plan starts at just five dollars a month you can choose a monthly or annual plan and
每个人都能找到适合好奇心流计划的起价，每月仅需 5 美元，您可以选择月度或年度计划，
get access to thousands of hours of quality content and is available on multiple devices like your TV computer and also mobile devices
访问数千小时的优质内容，并且可以在电视、电脑和移动设备等多种设备上使用
so you can watch your favorite content on the go all content on curiosity stream is factual so
这样您就可以随时随地观看您喜欢的内容好奇心流上的所有内容都是真实的，所以
there's a big focus on education whether it's science technology or history the documentaries are informative and engaging obviously I really like science
无论是科学技术还是历史，都非常注重教育，纪录片内容丰富且引人入胜，显然我真的很喜欢科学
and technology so I really like the series called Engineering in the future which
和技术，所以我真的很喜欢“未来工程”系列
covers the metaverse hyperloop technology space exploration flying cars but also includes a documentary about Timber skyscrapers go to curiositystream.com jamesbrussin or scan
涵盖了元宇宙超级高铁技术、太空探索飞行汽车，还包括一部关于木结构摩天大楼的纪录片，请访问cururitystream.com jamesbrussin或scan
the QR code for unlimited access to the world's top documentaries
二维码无限制观看全球顶级纪录片
and non-fiction series and for my fans use promo code James Bruton and you'll get 25 off so
和非小说系列，对于我的粉丝，使用促销代码 James Bruton 即可享受 25 折优惠
click the link below or go to curiositystream.com jamesbroughton and save 25 right now right time to get back to the attacks so
单击下面的链接或访问curusstream.com jamesbroughton 并立即节省25 美元以立即返回攻击，以便
I made the whole thing four times so we've got four legs each one has two servos so
我把整个事情做了四次，所以我们有四条腿，每条腿都有两个伺服系统，所以
that's eight servos but then there's another four servos at the top and that's going to enable the robot to turn so
这是八个伺服系统，但顶部还有另外四个伺服系统，这将使机器人能够转动
we've got a plate that goes on the bottom and the top and I've just got some bolts which are put through there
我们有一个位于底部和顶部的板，我刚刚有一些螺栓穿过那里
so we've got pivot Points and then we've got a Servo for each leg that
所以我们有枢轴点，然后我们有每条腿的伺服系统
runs on a larger gear on the top plate so that
在顶板上更大的齿轮上运行，以便
we can swing the legs outwards I thought it was a shame to tear the head and
我们可以把腿向外摆动 我觉得撕破头是一种耻辱
body off the original at A T so I'm printing a new one and this is printed on the lolsbot Tas long bed
主体与 A T 的原件不同，所以我正在打印一个新的，这是打印在 lolsbot Tas 长床上的
which has a really long bed for big parts so
它有一个非常长的床，可以容纳大零件，所以
my proportions aren't quite the same as the original toy but I'm pretty happy with the way it's turned out and
我的比例与原来的玩具不太一样，但我对它的结果非常满意
I think mechanically it's going to be pretty solid the headphones printing right now but we're going to put some Electronics in so
我认为从机械角度来看，现在的耳机打印将会非常坚固，但我们将放入一些电子设备，以便
as usual I've got an Arduino Mega that's more than enough to control those servos and
和往常一样，我有一个 Arduino Mega，它足以控制那些伺服系统，
it's got this piece of strip board with all these wires broken out of it with power and
它有一块带状板，所有这些电线都通过电源从上面断开，并且
the signal distribution for the 12 servos it's got an RC receiver on it the orange thing on there that's because
12 个舵机的信号分布，上面有一个 RC 接收器，上面有橙色的东西，那是因为
we're going to be using my universal remote I made which is a DSM remote so check that out and
我们将使用我制作的通用遥控器，它是 DSM 遥控器，因此请检查一下并
my channel right let's uh try and get all this wired up so we've got all those Electronics installed and
我的频道对了，让我们呃尝试将所有这些都连接起来，这样我们就安装了所有这些电子设备并且
the cables rooted as best possible and zip tied on and we've also got the head installed the Arduino lives in there and
电缆尽可能固定并用拉链绑好，我们还安装了 Arduino 的头部，
the main battery lives right at the back so I've just tied the controller to the servos for now so
主电池位于后面，所以我现在只是将控制器连接到伺服系统，所以
they all Bend in the same direction and you can see the whole thing goes up and
它们都向同一个方向弯曲，你可以看到整个物体上升并且
down as it bends its legs as you'd expect and also quite helpfully it can stand on one leg so
当它像你期望的那样弯曲它的腿时，它会向下弯曲，并且它可以用一条腿站立，这也很有帮助
those stabilizing feet really help to keep it upright you wouldn't be able to do that
那些稳定脚确实有助于保持直立，但你做不到
with one of my open dog projects but it would just fall over in that
与我的一个开放狗项目一起，但它会在那个项目中倒塌
direction but in order to take steps with one foot at a time what we actually need is it goes forwards is all
方向，但为了一步一步地迈出一步，我们真正需要的是向前走就是全部
of the other feet to slide back in a perfectly straight line now this is actually quite a complicated mechanism here to do
现在，其他脚以完美的直线向后滑动，这实际上是一个相当复杂的机制
that and we're going to do it properly so
我们会正确地做到这一点
we're going to calculate some inverse kinematics I did a more in-depth video about this before where I builds a simple robot arm
我们将计算一些逆运动学，之前我制作了一个关于此的更深入的视频，在那里我构建了一个简单的机器人手臂
the calculations I did for this allow me to position the end of the arm into Cartesian coordinates
我为此所做的计算使我能够将手臂的末端定位到笛卡尔坐标中
that means up and down and left and
这意味着向上、向下、向左
right in straight lines the code running calculates the required joint angles for the two joints I use Pythagoras Theorem and
直线运行的代码计算出两个关节所需的关节角度，我使用毕达哥拉斯定理和
trigonometry to work out the angles the at 80 is very similar if we consider the leg to be a triangle so
如果我们将腿视为三角形，则计算 80 度角度的三角学非常相似，所以
first I worked out the angles from the required length of the leg which is easy because
首先，我从所需的腿长度算出角度，这很容易，因为
we know all three sides once this is done we can set the leg length and
一旦完成，我们就知道所有三个边，我们可以设置腿的长度和
the code will work out the angles next we need to move the foot back and forth we can just imagine that
代码将计算出接下来我们需要来回移动脚的角度，我们可以想象一下
the leg is a straight line since we can set its length already so
腿是一条直线，因为我们已经可以设置它的长度了
we can imagine another right angle triangle where we give it the distance we want to move back and
我们可以想象另一个直角三角形，我们给它我们想要向后移动的距离，
forth the height of the body and then use trigonometry to work out the shoulder angle and
计算出身体的高度，然后利用三角函数计算出肩部角度，
the new leg length we pass the new leg length onto the previous calculation and
新的腿长我们将新的腿长传递到之前的计算中，并且
then the body will stay at the same height as the foot moves back and
然后当脚向后移动时，身体将保持在相同的高度
forth the only thing I didn't take into account properly was this piece of the leg here because these two joints don't meet
我唯一没有正确考虑的是这里的腿的一部分，因为这两个关节没有相遇
so it's not a perfect triangle but I just ignored that and it works perfectly well so now we can actually move that
所以它不是一个完美的三角形，但我只是忽略了它，它工作得很好，所以现在我们实际上可以移动它
body up and
身体向上并且
down as we did before but instead of just moving those servos directly coupled to the stick we're actually calculating trigonometry and
像我们之前所做的那样向下，但我们实际上是在计算三角函数，而不是直接移动那些直接耦合到操纵杆的伺服系统
working out the leg length and now I can pretty much slide backwards and forwards as well in a straight line so
计算出腿的长度，现在我几乎可以直线前后滑动，所以
if you look at the cabinet behind me you'll find that
如果你看看我身后的柜子你会发现
body is tracking it at some point those servos do reach their end stops though and
身体在某个时刻跟踪它，但这些伺服系统确实到达了终点站，并且
also the cheap hobby servos have quite low tolerance feedback pots in probably about 10 tolerance so that
此外，廉价的业余爱好伺服系统具有相当低的容差反馈电位器，大约为 10 容差，因此
means you probably don't get a linear response out of them that along with the broken triangle at the knee means that
意味着你可能不会从它们中得到线性响应，再加上膝盖处的破碎三角形意味着
we don't get a perfectly straight line in any direction but we've got enough that we can make it walk and
我们在任何方向上都没有一条完美的直线，但我们已经有足够的直线可以使它行走并且
the legs move backwards and forwards in pretty much a straight line so we can take steps so
腿几乎以一条直线前后移动，这样我们就可以迈出步子
obviously I can move the feet independently and
显然我可以独立移动双脚
we can put a step sequencer together to make it take steps you can see the foot doesn't track the ground perfectly but
我们可以将一个步进音序器放在一起，让它采取步骤，你可以看到脚并没有完美地跟踪地面，但是
it's good enough for our purposes there's one other issue we need to solve though if I move my hand along the table
这对于我们的目的来说已经足够了，但是如果我沿着桌子移动我的手，我们还需要解决另一个问题
here
这里
so it tracks in a perfectly straight line You'll see that my arm gets longer in this position and
所以它沿着一条完美的直线运动 你会发现我的手臂在这个位置变长了
it gets longer in this position as we move further away from the center but you'll also notice that
当我们远离中心时，它在这个位置变得更长，但你也会注意到
my shoulder is moving a lot more than my elbow the elbow joint hardly ever moves and
我的肩膀比肘部移动得更多，肘关节几乎从不移动
my shoulder makes most of the motion so
我的肩膀进行了大部分的运动，所以
if we were just to send the two servos of the leg to another position in a straight line like this then one
如果我们只是像这样将腿的两个伺服系统发送到直线上的另一个位置，那么一个
has to move further than the other
必须比对方走得更远
and if we just send them at the speed that the servos will go at which
如果我们只是以伺服系统的速度发送它们
is their maximum speed then basically one is going to get there first the other one will catch up later and that
是他们的最大速度，那么基本上一个人会先到达那里，另一个人会稍后赶上，并且
means we won't be moving in a perfectly straight line anymore when I'm driving the joints manually effectively I'm scrolling through all the
意味着当我有效地手动驱动关节时，我们将不再沿着完美的直线移动，我正在滚动浏览所有
positions from A to B
从 A 到 B 的位置
because I'm moving this thick quite slowly through all the positions over time and
因为随着时间的推移，我在所有位置上移动得很慢
the math is being calculated 100 times a second to work out the joint angles and
每秒计算 100 次数学计算以计算出关节角度
therefore the leg tracks in a straight line from point A to point B but if I was just to suddenly send a
因此，腿从 A 点到 B 点沿直线运动，但如果我只是突然发送一个
step from one position to the next then those two joints will move them maximum speed
从一个位置走到下一个位置然后这两个关节将以最大速度移动
and one will get there faster than the other so what we need is something that
一个人会比另一个人更快地到达那里，所以我们需要的是
will manually scroll through all the positions but do it automatically when we specify two points and to do that
将手动滚动浏览所有位置，但当我们指定两个点时会自动滚动并执行此操作
we can use the Arduino ramp Library the simplest demo for that is specifying two points and then opening a Serial plotter and
我们可以使用 Arduino RAM 库，最简单的演示是指定两个点，然后打开串行绘图仪并
seeing the interpolation between them which is a nice straight line instead of a square wave or a step that
看到它们之间的插值，这是一条漂亮的直线，而不是方波或阶梯
new interpolated value is fed into the inverse kinematics so all the way through that value changing over time recalculates the joint angles
新的插值被输入到逆运动学中，因此随着时间的推移，该值不断变化，重新计算关节角度
and our feet move in a straight line from position to position I'm also using motion filtering on my control sticks and
我们的脚从一个位置直线移动到另一个位置我也在我的控制杆上使用运动过滤
on the servos themselves on the output so
在伺服系统本身的输出上，所以
I made a video specifically about this you should check out where I made a robot head with really cheap servos and
我专门制作了一个关于此的视频，你应该看看我在哪里用非常便宜的伺服系统制作了一个机器人头，
controlled it with an 8-bit Arduino and you can see the Motions are really smooth there as I move around and
用 8 位 Arduino 控制它，你可以看到当我四处走动时，动作非常流畅
basically all I'm doing is taking a large percentage of the previous value in the loop and
基本上我所做的就是在循环中获取前一个值的很大一部分，然后
only a small percentage of the new ones so the values can't change too quick and
仅占新值的一小部分，因此值不会变化太快
we get this lovely deceleration on the moves so
我们在移动时得到了可爱的减速，所以
now if I switch a switch on the controller we've got a timed sequence running that
现在，如果我打开控制器上的开关，我们就会得到一个运行的定时序列
lifts each foot in turn pretty much the way a dog walks if I push forward on one of my control sticks then
如果我向前推动其中一根控制杆，那么就会依次抬起每只脚，就像狗走路一样
it takes the multiple of
它需要的倍数
that control stick and moves all of the feet backwards which are on the ground and the one forward which
控制杆并将所有在地面上的脚向后移动，并向前移动一只脚
is off the ground and so it walks along pretty convincingly and
离开地面，所以它的行走非常令人信服
pretty much how an AT-AT walks flicking another switch causes it to lift diagonal legs and if I turn one of the controllers
与 AT-AT 行走的方式差不多，轻按另一个开关会使其抬起对角线腿，如果我转动其中一个控制器
that causes the legs to swing out at the appropriate time to make it turn the legs don't share a common pivot point
这会导致腿在适当的时间向外摆动以使其转动 腿不共享公共枢轴点
and that pivot point isn't in the middle of the robot which means the feet should actually move position in and
并且该枢轴点不在机器人的中间，这意味着脚实际上应该移动位置
out as it rotates round but I didn't care about that and it's light enough it doesn't matter so
当它旋转时会出来，但我不在乎，而且它足够轻，所以没关系
it walks okay it's very wobbly side to side you'll notice though although that
它走起来还不错，但左右摇摆得很厉害，尽管如此，你会注意到
only happens when it walks forwards if I reverse things and walk backwards which
仅当它向前行走时才会发生，如果我反转事物并向后行走，
I can do just by pulling the stick in the other direction then it's actually much more stable you'll notice his bottom is
我可以通过向另一个方向拉动棍子来做到这一点，那么它实际上更稳定，你会注意到他的底部是
much more stable than the head was when it was walking the other way
比头部向相反方向行走时稳定得多
and that is because
那是因为
the head is making it front heavy already but when it pushes all its legs back apart from the one that's in the
头部已经使它前面很重，但是当它把所有的腿向后推，与里面的腿分开时
air that
空气那个
makes it even more front heavy I tried to add Mass to the back by putting a battery on the back outside the
使它的前部更重我试图通过将电池放在后部外侧来增加后部的质量
back
后退
and also having some nuts there to add some extra mass it's pretty hard to compensate for the 300 grams hanging so
而且还在那里放了一些坚果来增加一些额外的质量，很难补偿 300 克的悬挂重量，所以
far out the front though
虽然在前面很远
[Music] foreign
[音乐]外国
foreign [Music]
外国[音乐]
that means at iet's will work if the Star Wars was real life you'd actually be able to send one into battle and
这意味着如果星球大战是现实生活中的，那么你实际上可以派一个人去战斗，并且
it will walk along it's quite good to know that they're statically stable so it can take one leg off the ground and
it will walk along it's quite good to know that they're statically stable so it can take one leg off the ground and
still stand there with it off the ground it doesn't need to put it down again to catch itself because
仍然站在那儿，它离开地面，不需要再次放下它来抓住自己，因为
we all know what happens when at 18s fall over I'm going to publish all the cannon go for this project so
我们都知道当 18 岁的时候摔倒时会发生什么，我将发布这个项目的所有大炮，所以
if you want to have a look at it or build your own you can and that's on GitHub it's totally open source
如果你想看看或者构建自己的，你可以，这在 GitHub 上，它是完全开源的
so if you want to support me through patreon or YouTube channel membership then those links are in the description below and patrons
因此，如果您想通过 patreon 或 YouTube 频道会员资格来支持我，那么这些链接位于下面的描述和订阅者中
and YouTube channel members can get access to all the videos up to a week early sneak peeks and
YouTube 频道会员最多可以提前一周预览所有视频，
pictures of what's coming up and Discord benefits
即将发生的事情和 Discord 福利的图片